nutraingredients-usa.com 2015-12-26

# privacy-policy | Privacy & Cookie Policy

Updated as at 1 July 2012

## 1\. Introduction

This website is made available to you by William Reed Business Media ("William Reed", "we", "our" or "us") (the "Website"). This privacy policy outlines how we may use your personal information and forms part of the Terms of Use of the Websites.

"Personal information" refers to any information which refers to you personally such as your name, e-mail address and postal address. Please read this privacy policy to understand how we use your personal information after it has been collected by us.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from to time. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page so please visit this Privacy Policy regularly.

## 2\. When do we collect data?

We may collect personal information from you when you do the following through our Websites:

  * order products and subscriptions from us;
  * register as a user on one or more of our Websites;
  * provide content through our online communities;
  * apply for jobs with us;
  * register to receive our newsletters; and
  * contact us with a question or complaint.

We also collect certain information automatically about visitors to our Websites, as described in the section headed "Cookies" below.

## 3\. What personal information do we collect from you?

The personal information we may collect from you includes your:

  * name;
  * postal address;
  * phone number (land line, mobile and fax);
  * credit or debit card details; and
  * email address.

If you apply for a job with us through the Websites you also have the opportunity to upload your CV to us.

## 4\. What do we do with your personal information?

When you give us any personal information as indicated above, we use your personal information to:

  * enable you to use any services that we may from time to time provide through the Websites;
  * enable you to become a registered user on one or more of our Websites;
  * process your transaction or subscription and correspond with you accordingly;
  * provide you, in accordance with your communications preferences, with information about our products and services, our latest news or special offers which may be of interest to you;
  * track activity on our Websites for market research purposes so that we can improve the usefulness and content of the Websites but, in carrying out such activity, we use the personal information in aggregate and on an anonymous basis;
  * stop you posting or sending offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on our Websites or where you otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on the Websites. This may involve informing relevant third parties such as your employer, e-mail/Internet provider and law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour; and
  * for Website administration (including enabling us to respond to any comments on the Websites or feedback you may give us).

## 5\. To whom do we pass your personal information?

We may share personal information collected via the Websites within our corporate group including William Reed Holdings Limited, William Reed Business Media Ltd, HIM Ltd, William Reed Business Media SAS and William Reed Business Media Inc. Otherwise, we will only disclose personal information to government bodies and law enforcement agencies, successors in title to our business and suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf.

## 6\. International transfers of personal information

On the basis that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data across international boundaries. In particular, we will hold your personal information in the UK and France, and we may transfer it to the USA to a service provider who may host the Websites and store personal information on our behalf.

While some territories outside the European Economic Area may not have laws which provide the same level of protection for personal information as those inside the European Economic Area, we will ensure that your personal information is protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy wherever it is processed by us.

By browsing the Websites and submitting personal information to us, you acknowledge our processing of your personal information on this basis.

## 7\. Cookies

When you view our Websites we may store information on the hard drive of your computer or on your mobile device in the form of a "cookie" (essentially a small text file). Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, William Reed) are called "first party cookies". Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called "third party cookies". Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like advertising, videos and website analytics services). The parties that set these third party cookies can recognise your computer both when it visits the website in question and also when it visits certain other websites.

Cookies can remain on your computer or mobile device for different periods of time. Some cookies are ‘session cookies’, meaning that they exist only while your website browser is open and are deleted automatically once you close your browser. Other cookies are ‘permanent cookies’, meaning that they survive after your browser is closed and can be used by websites to recognise your computer when you later re-open your browser and browse the internet again.

We use cookies for several reasons. For example, cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our website. Third parties serve cookies through our website for advertising, analytics and other purposes. This is described in more detail below.

The specific types of cookies served through the Websites, either by William Reed or third parties and the purposes they perform are described in the table below:

Types of cookie | What they do  
---|---  
First Party (This website’s primary domain) | ASP.NET_SessionId  
__atuvc  
.ASPXAUTH  
5e831a0b0bc6a8b74a8e106ba442439a  
1a37338d574b3f5c95c0957b89dd0218  
TransactionId  
pfps_poll  
PHPSESSID  
googtrans  
NCS2012_UCOOKIEID  
OTISTRAILID_NCS2012  
SECTION  
OTISTRAILID_RESTSHOW2012  
RESTSHOW2012  
RESTSHOW2012_UCOOKIEID  
SECTION  
TTSCODE  
AnonymousUserId  
BrowserSession  
ASPSESSIONIDSCSBDSRB  
dnm_isoa2  
PHPSESSID%28_%29  
acceptCount   
cookiesaccepted  
check  
User_WebSite  
Logon_WebSite  
LoginCookieCheck  
User_CandidateCVServices  
Logon_CandidateCVServices  
User_RecruiterServices  
Logon_RecruiterServices  
twister_Collapsed  
twister_Expanded  
CookieTest  
User_MobileSite  
Logon_MobileSite  
cookieNotification  
Third Party | ASPSESSIONIDQSSABSAR  
Expo%2EHomePage  
**Performance and functionality cookies** | These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our Websites but are non-essential to their use. However, without these cookies, certain functionality (like videos) may become unavailable.  
First Party | flyUpCounter  
deviceType  
dnm_isoa2  
Session_Jobseeker  
Session_CandidateCVServices  
RecruiterCVServicesSettings  
Session_Mobile  
Third Party | PREF  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
Local storage  
**Analytics and customisation cookies** | These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how the website is being used or how effective are marketing campaigns are, or to help us customise the website for you.  
First Party | __utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmz  
dnm_c  
dnm_l  
dnm_s  
dnm_r  
JobListing  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchPage  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchCount  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchItems  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchListingPage  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchPageSize  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchOrder  
WebSite_LatestJobSearchID  
WebSite_LatestSearchRecruiterID  
WebSite_LatestSearchFirstJobID  
WebSite_LatestSearchLastJobID  
WebSite_SearchPageLink  
CampaignClickThroughID  
JBEClickThroughID  
JBEClickThroughJobID  
RSSClickThroughJobID  
WidgetClickThroughDomain  
WidgetClickThroughJobID  
iPhoneClickThroughJobID  
Session_RecruiterHub  
dnm_guestc  
dnm_activepp  
read_news_ids  
DL_Auth  
Frame  
Third Party | IMRID  
V5  
**Advertising cookies** | These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.  
Third Party | TestIfCookie  
TestIfCookieP  
dyncdn  
pbw  
pbwmaj6  
pdomid  
pid  
vs  
sasd  
ad_track  
_drt_  
test_cookie  
id  
OABLOCK  
OACAP  
OACBLOCK  
OACCAP  
OAID  
OASCAP  
OASCCAP  
**Social networking cookies** | These cookies are used to enable you to share pages and content that you find interesting on our website through third party social networking websites.  
Third Party | psc  
uid  
uit  
uvc  
X-LI-IDC  
X-LI-IDC  
__stid  
__uset  
guest_id  
  
You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies. You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use our website; however, your access to some functionality and areas of our Websites may be restricted.

If you would like to find out more information about cookies and your rights to control their use, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

## 8\. Linking to other websites

The Websites contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These websites have their own privacy policies and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

## 9\. IP Addresses

We study visitor trends since we are interested in the successful dissemination of information through the Websites. Our server creates log files of information such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address from your network, what pages were explored and the length of your visit. Analysis software is used to generate reports which help us to learn more about how we can enhance your experience with the Websites. This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you. The log files are regularly purged.

An IP address is a number designated for your computer by your Internet service provider to provide access to the Internet. We may use your IP address to gather aggregate information on use. But we will only be able to identify you individually if we have the means of linking the IP address to you as a particular user. This usually requires access to additional information which we do not seek.

## 10\. Your right to see your personal information

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold on you and to have any errors in that information corrected. We may charge a small fee for such requests where this is permitted under applicable law You also have the right to ask us to stop processing your personal information on compelling legitimated grounds. You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the details provided below.

## How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy at any time, please contact us using the following details:

_For visitors from the UK:_

The data controller of personal information collected about you through this Website is William Reed Business Media Ltd, a limited liability company registered in England and Wales (registered number is 2883992) whose registered office is at Broadfield Park, Crawley, West Sussex RH11 9RT.

You can write to us at the address above (marked for the attention of the Company Secretary or e-mail us at: [robert.proctor@wrbm.com](mailto:robert.proctor@wrbm.com).

_For visitors from France:_

The data controller of personal information collected about you through this Website is William Reed Business Media SAS, a limited liability company registered in France (registered number 429 315 971) whose registered office is at 335, rue Vendemiaire, Le Belem – 34400 Montpellier.

You can write to us at the address above (marked for the attention of the Company Secretary) or e-mail us at: [robert.proctor@wrbm.com](mailto:robert.proctor@wrbm.com).
